Jennifer W. Nelson

12687 Gibraltar Drive San Diego, CA 92128 858.705.3201

jenniferwnelson@sbcglobal.net http://jennifernelson.io

www.linkedin.com/pub/jennifer-wallick-nelson-pmp/8/840/658/ http://github.com/jwncoexists

Summary

An experienced software developer who loves making ideas come to life on the screen! Products I've helped create include: software to automatically appraise the value of real estate using neural network models (patent being used by Zillow), and software for a 3D xray machine to automatically detect soldering defects on computer circuit boards. I just recently released an e-learning website where users earn HR continuing education credits.

I am passionate and driven to create quality software applications, on schedule, and within budget. I love taking an idea from concept through to implementation. Here's more about me:

Goal-oriented, dedicated, highly motivated Believe in behavior-driven & test-driven development Strong people and communication skills Fast learner who thrives on problem solving PMP certification August 2011

Objectives

Test Driven, Web Development position using Ruby on Rails

Professional Skills

Ruby, Rails, C++, C, AngularJS, Javascript, JQuery
Relational Databases, PostgreSQL, SQLServer, SQL
Git, GitHub, OOD, Bootstrap, YouTube & Vimeo API.s Google Charts API,
Redis, Resque, Amazon S3, CSS, Devise
Test Driven Development, Behavior Driven Development, Cucumber, RSpec, Capistrano

Education

M.S. Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN B.A. With Honors Mathematics, Macalester College, St. Paul, MN

Employment History

Nelson Software Consulting, San Diego, CA

Software Developer, September 2013 – Present

Developed several RoR web applications including an e-learning application for video-based training courses which are certified for continuing education credits. BDD Test Driven & RESTful Development with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, JQuery, Javascript, Cucumber, RSpec, AWS, user authentication & membership, emails, and Resque background processing. Currently working on a new RoR site for SanDiegoWedding.com.

DR Systems, San Diego, CA

Manager of Project Management, July 2004 - November 2013

In charge of project management department responsible for the implementations of medical imaging solutions at customer sites. Responsibilities include staffing, financial forecasts, definition of departmental goals and procedures, managing personnel, and day-to-day operations.

Sympozium Online Training, Vista, CA

Information Technology Manager, February 2003 - February 2004

Designed and managed IT infrastructure and website for online training company. Improved system up-time through failure analysis and redesign of hardware. Improved efficiency with design and development of an internal learning management system, assisted with proposals and demonstrations for the sales and marketing departments.

Nelson Motivation Inc., San Diego, CA

Software Specialist, June 1997 – February 2003

Designed, developed system to estimate shipping costs for the warehouse. Maintained customer databases and developed successful e-mail marketing campaigns. Set up and maintained computer network and software. Designed, developed and maintained company website. Designed and created the largest selection of e-documents for consumer sales available on Amazon.com

System One, La Jolla, CA

Software Developer, February 1996 – February 1997

Designed and developed software for a variety of clients including 1) 9-1-1 call handling software, 2) event planner software, 3) exercise tracking software for exercise equipment primarily using Visual Basic, Visual C++ and Crystal Reports.

Hewlett Packard, San Diego, CA

Software Engineering Manager, April 1994 – February 1996

Led a team of people responsible for designing, developing and testing software products for an X-ray inspection system for computer circuit boards. All products developed with an object-oriented design using C++, C, Pascal and Visual Basic.

HNC Software, San Diego, CA

Project Manager, June 1992 – April 1994

In charge of design and development of a commercial software product to automatically appraise real estate. Developed under Microsoft Windows in Visual Basic and C, and utilized HNC's neural network modeling technology.

Four PI Systems, San Diego, CA Computer Scientist, March 1986 – June 1992 Designed, developed a variety of software products for an automated x-ray inspection system of computer circuit boards including: 1) an object-oriented software development environment, 2) parallel processing machine control software, 3) operator interface software, and 4) CAD interface software.

Certifications, Publications

Certification: Ruby on Rails

December 2013 BLOC Apprenticeships

Publication: "Replacement PACS: Planning for a Successful DICOM Migration"

November 2011

Health Information Executives

Certification: Project Management Professional (PMP)

August 2011

Project Management Institute

Patent: "Real Estate Real Estate Appraisal using Predictive Modeling"

1994

US Patent Office

963,908

San Diego, CA